MITCHELL R. DORSEY

4206 33rd Avenue, Cincinnati, OH 45209

(513) 203-3344 -- Github: https://github.com/mitchdorsey

Email: mitchellrdorsey@gmail.com -- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mitchelldorsey/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Developer searching for a role that allows me to use my adaptability and communication skills. Constantly broadening my skill set both technically and mentally. Past work experiences have given me strengths in thinking on my feet and continuously being flexible. Programmer that enjoys collaborating with a resourceful team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Object Oriented Programming: C#, .NET, .NET Core, Java (Android framework)

Web Application Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MVC, Bootstrap, XML (Android framework), Python **Database Programming:** SQL, table design and creation

Development tools and techniques: Entity Framework, Agile, Git, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, MySQL Workbench, Android Studio, unit testing (MS Unit), integration testing, TDD, command line navigation

EDUCATION

Tech Elevator - Cincinnati, Ohio

September 2018 - December 2018

14-week .NET coding bootcamp learning database programming, .NET frameworks and design patterns, web application security, server side programming and client side web programming

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Family Reading Tracker --- http://familyreadingtracker.apphb.com/

• Web app developed in C#/.Net using MVC pattern, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Stock Market App

• Web app developed in C#/. Net Core using MVC pattern, Stock Market Web API, Javascript

American Football Score Keeper --- Android mobile app

• Developed in Java and XML allowing the user to keep track of the score between 2 teams

Coffee Purchase --- Android mobile app

Developed in Java and XML simulating a coffee transaction that integrates an Email Intent

Book Listing App --- Android mobile app

Developed in Java and XML, lists the published books on a given topic using the Google Books API

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

VRI - Franklin, Ohio

March 2020 – August 2023

Software Engineer

- Created an application which automated a repetitive task, saving a manager up to 3 hours per week
- Performed or supported biweekly QA and production software releases
- Guided new developers through application changes that require using a third-party low code platform

Physna - Cincinnati, Ohio

February 2019 - December 2019

Junior Software Developer

- Implemented features on object-oriented web app and desktop client app
- Coordinated with Application Engineer to evaluate and improve software
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches
- Built desktop client installer file used for distribution